Guide to the Stanford Staffers Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Staffers records
1951-1999
SC0548
Stanford Staffers.
8.75 Linear feet
Records, 1951-1995, include correspondence, publications, financial records, publicity, program information, photographs, clippings, and video taped interviews (1998-1999).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Stanford Staffers, 1998, 2003.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Stanford Staffers began in 1951 as the Distaff Club, a group of women staff members who gathered for lunch and companionship. Faculty wives served as sponsors, hosting teas and luncheons at their campus homes. Ann Sterling, wife of the late President J.E. Wallace Sterling, was the founding faculty wife-sponsor.
In 1978, the group agreed to admit men and changed its name to Stanford Staffers. Organization goals include providing career support and sharing resources, networking, doing community service, developing and cultivating a diverse workplace and enjoying social contacts. Its activities range from monthly lectures on subjects as diverse as public service and tax planning to an "attitude adjustment hour," held every other month at a restaurant lounge after work.
Description of the Collection
Records, 1951-1995, include correspondence, publications, financial records, publicity, program information, photographs, clippings, and video taped interviews (1998-1999).
Access Terms
Stanford Staffers.; Employees--California.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-1998-143
  - " 100 Years of Diversity" buttons (1991 ?) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - 4 audio tapes: Irma Jean's Recollections 1991; 3 music tapes (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - 40th Anniversary planning correspondence 1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - AMA Secretary's Program 1991 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Article clippings, correspondence, and records 1972-1973 (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Article clippings, correspondence, and records 1972-1973 (20f 2) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Article clippings, notes, and correspondence 1951-1987 (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Article clippings, notes, and correspondence 1951-1987 (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Article clippings, notes, and correspondence 1951-1987 (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Article clippings & notes (blue folder) 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Article clippings, notes, records, correspondence 1975-1977 (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Article clippings, notes, records, correspondence 1975-1977 (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Articles & photos, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Articles & photos, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Articles & photos, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Articles & photos, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Bank of the West check book 1984-1986 (empty) (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Bank of the West statements 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bank of the West statements 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Big Game 1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Blank membership forms (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Catering price lists 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Completed membership forms 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Constitution 1980s -1990s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Copying resources 1991 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1987 -1990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence cards 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence & financial records 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence & flyer announcement 1991 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence & miscellaneous member information 1977-1978 (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence & miscellaneous member information 1977-1978 (2 of2) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence & newsletter 1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -Notes to Staff' 1990-1991 " (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence & past members roster 1991 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, photos, publications 1990 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence & publications 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence & publications 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence & records 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence regarding Giants game 1991 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence regarding June potluck 1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence regarding Spring Fling event 1991 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence regarding staff brochure 1988 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence regarding Staffers donors 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence & T-shirt design 1991 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence & time sheet 1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence/newspaper clipping 1990 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Database Information (membership) 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - December Newsletter 1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Disabled Staff Forum proposal 1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Distaff 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Distaff Club records, 1975-1979 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Distaff Club records, 1975-1979 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Distaff Club records, 1975-1979 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Distaff Club records, 1975-1979 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Distaff Club records, 1978-1980 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Distaff Club records, 1978-1980 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Distaff Club records, 1978-1980 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Distaff Club records, 1978-1980 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Distaff Club records, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Distaff Club records, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Distaff Club records, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Distaff Club records, 1980-1983 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Distaff Club records, 1980-1983 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Distaff Club records, 1980-1983 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Distaff Club records, 1980-1983 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Distaff Club records, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Distaff Club records, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Distaff Club records, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Distaff Club records, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Distaff Notes 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Distaff Notes 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Documents & correspondence 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Documents, correspondence, Staffers Directory 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Election notes & slate of volunteers 1990 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Expense reimbursement vouchers (empty) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Expenses to reimburse 1990-91 (?) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fellowships: Wigner 1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Financial documents 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Financial documents 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Financial documents & correspondence 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Financial documents & correspondence 1991 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Financial records 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Flyer originals 1991 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Flyers & correspondence 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Flyers & publications (folder labeled iOne Of Eachi) 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Front Line 1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Front Line & correspondence 1990 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Front Line March 1991 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Goals/duties/calendar 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Graphics for name tags 1990 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - January Front Line 1991 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - January Front Line originals 1991 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - July Staffers 1990 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Kennedy Holiday Party 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Labels for renewed members 1990 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Members list & correspondence 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Membership 1979-1982 (1 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Membership 1979-1982 (2 of 2) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Membership 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Membership brochure 1990 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Membership dues 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Membership forms 1990s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership labels (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Membership labels (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Membership labels/correspondence 1991 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Membership materials 1990 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Memento/photo album (black leather with gold leaf) 1951-1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous papers related to Staffers' 40th Anniversary celebration 1991 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous papers/publications (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous records 1983-1985 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters & clippings 1991 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters & correspondence 1990 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters & correspondence 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Nominations 1991 (brown folder) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Notes: chronology of major events in Stanford Staffers! history 1991 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Notes & correspondence 1973-1975 (20f2) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Notes & correspondence 1973-1975 (2 of2) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Notes & correspondence 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Notes & correspondence 1990-1991 (small red binder) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Notes & correspondence 1991 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - November Front Line 1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Office newsletter/correspondence 1990 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Officers' Roster 1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Original membership flyer 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Overview of 1951-1987 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Overview of 1951-1987 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Paid members/cards issued list 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Paul Hamrah Gift Checks 1991 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Photos 1990 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Photos 1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Photos (date?) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Photos (envelope) (1986-1987?) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Postage (1991 ?) (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Potluck & sale 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Program Announcements 1964-1966 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Program Announcements 1964-1966 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Program ideas 1972-1974 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Promotional catalog & notes 1990s (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Proposed calendar 1990 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Publications 1991-1995 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Publications and correspondence 1990 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Publications & correspondence 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Publications & notes 1990 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Publicity 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Recorded minutes of board meetings 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Records and notes (thin red binder) 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Records & correspondence 1960-1970 (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Records & correspondence 1960-1970 (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Records & correspondence 1970-1971 (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Records & correspondence 1970-1971 (20f2) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Records, financial documents, & correspondence 1969-1971 (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Records, financial documents, & correspondence 1969-1971 (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Records, notes, and correspondence 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Recruiting Brochure original copies 1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Remembrances 1951-1991 (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Remembrances 1951-1991 (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Renewed members list 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Safety Issues For Women 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Secretarial Forum -HRO/Staffers (1991?) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - September Front Line 1990 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - September/October Front Line master 1990 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Shopping Trip 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Shopping trip 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Shopping trip 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Shopping Trip 1990 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Spring Fling program 1991 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Spring Lecture - correspondence regarding event dates (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Staff Vision 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Staffers Boards for Fall 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Staffers brochure 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Staffers credit union account 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Staffers Mailer 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Staffers Membership 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Staffers Mission brochure 1990 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Staffers Newsletter 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Staffers newsletter header May 1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Staffers questionnaire & responses 1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Staffers records 1976-1977 (white binder) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Staffers Transition 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stamped letter addressed to Distaff Club 1976 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Credit Union statements 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Publication Services order forms 1989 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Stanford Publication Services order forms 1989 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Stanford Publication Services (red folder) 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Staffers 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Staffers lists 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Stanford Staffers meetings 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1985-1986 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1985-1986 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1991-1993 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Staffers records, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Staffers Treasurer' s Report 1989-1992 (thick orange (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Stanford University Campus Report April 24, 1991 (3 copies) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Survey of interests and backgrounds 1980 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Treasureris Report 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Tresidder resources 1990 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Volunteer lists 1990 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Wine taster 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Wine tasting invitationlPGM Originals 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Wines taster, 33137 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Interviews, Accession 2003-053
  The following interview questions were asked:
  Why they were interested and involved in Staffers.
  What kinds of organization and activities Staffers had during the interviewee's most active years.
  How they thought Staffers contributed to the well-being of Stanford employees.
  Their own experience and career path working at Stanford.
  - Interviews by Joyce Kiefer with Irma Jean Crouch, Ann Vellmer, Ethel LaPuyade, 1998, and Kimberly Thompson, 1999, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Interview by Joyce Kiefer with J. Truher, 1999, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)